Preliminary Guide to the John Beloff Papers, 1963-2001
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
John Beloff papers 1963-2001
Beloff, John
26 linear feet Extent: 19,050 Items
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
RL.00103
Language: English.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research; however, some of the materials in this collection are not immediately accessible, because they require further processing before use.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
Received as a gift in 1992, 1995, 1999 and 2002.
Biographical Note
Parapsychologist and professor of psychology at the University of Edinburgh; editor of the Journal of the Society for Psychical Research.
Collection Overview
Collection (acc.#s 92-098, 95-096, 99-337) (17,150 items, 23 linear feet; dated 1963-1999) contains correspondence, research materials, unpublished papers, other manuscripts, files relating to professional associations and journals, printed matter, and talks reflecting Beloff's work in the field of parapsychology. These items reflect Dr. Beloff's connections with parapsychologists throughout the world, including North America, Latin America, Europe, and Asia, including J.B. Rhine. Container lists have not been created for accessions from 1992 and 1995.
The addition (acc# 2002-0245) (1900 items, 3 linear feet; dated [1980s]-2001) consists primarily of correspondence files, reflecting Dr. Beloff's connections with parapsychologists throughout the world ([1980s]-2001). Also includes some manuscripts of articles/papers.
Subject Headings
Beloff, John; Psychical research; Parapsychology -- Research; Parapsychology -- Research -- Periodicals; Parapsychologists -- United States -- Correspondence; Mind and body; Parapsychology
Contents of Collection
- Accession #1999-0337
  - Benor (Box 1)
  - Editorial Correspondence (Box 1)
  - Referees 1993/1994 (Box 1)
  - David Ellis (Box 1)
  - Tony Cornell - Alan Gauld (Box 1)
  - Eisenbud - Lomax (Box 1)
  - Vernon Harrison (Box 1)
  - Michael Coleman 1992-1995 (Box 1)
  - U.T. Place (Box 1)
  - EUROP-PA (Box 1)
  - MarkZilberman (Box 1)
  - Gardner-Stepanek-Keil 1987/1992 (Box 1)
  - Imich Prize 1992/1993 (Box 1)
  - Raymond Bayless 1989-92 (Box 1)
  - Amorim 1990/1991 (Box 1)
  - Lampeter 1987/88 IISD (Box 2)
  - RelentlessQuestion 1987-1993 McFarland (Box 2)
  - Dorothy E. Warren 1991-1994 (2folders) (Box 2)
  - Guy Playfair 1986-1994 (Box 2)
  - Brazil - Carvalho (Box 2)
  - WillisHarman (Box 2)
  - Sommerhoff G (Box 2)
  - CambridgeConference (Box 2)
  - Winawer (Box 2)
  - MacLellan (Box 2)
  - Argentina/ Mexico South America/ Brazil (Box 2)
  - SPR Council (Box 2)
  - Fulvia Cariglia San MarinoConference (Box 2)
  - He, Hong Beijing (Box 2)
  - AlastairMacLellan (Box 2)
  - F.S. Roberts 1995- (Box 2)
  - American Miscellaneous Correspondence (Box 3)
  - Peter Mulacz (Box 3)
  - 1989-1995 JohnSmythies (Box 3)
  - Roy Willis (Box 3)
  - Colin Wilson (Box 3)
  - Susan Blackmore 1990-1995 (Box 3)
  - Alexander Imich 1990-1995 (Box 3)
  - Journal 1992 (Box 3)
  - Indian Parapsych. 1983/1985 Misc. (Box 3)
  - YaleConference (Box 3)
  - Takeshima (Box 3)
  - Stevenson (Box 3)
  - Philosophers Misc. 1988/1992 (Box 3)
  - Shang-Hai Correspondence (Box 3)
  - Hansen (Box 3)
  - Misc. Psychologists (Box 3)
  - Flew-Taylor (Box 3)
  - C. Tort (2folders) (Box 3)
  - Misc. Philosophers (Box 3)
  - Hoyt Edge - MichaelGross (Box 3)
  - Stafford Betty - PaulaFreeborn (Box 3)
  - Smythies ( U. of Virginia) Press 1986-1989 (2folders) (Box 4)
  - Mostyn Gilbert - Fraser Nicol 1989/90 (Box 4)
  - Italian Parapsychologists 1975-92 (Box 4)
  - International Conference on Parapsychology (Box 4)
  - Peoch (Box 4)
  - Chinese Parapsychology 1982-1988 (Box 4)
  - Soviet ParapsychologistsMisc. (Box 4)
  - 1985/1989 F.R.N.M. (Box 4)
  - Brian Inglis (Box 4)
  - "Miscellaneous"
    - Renee Hanes - Obituary, 1992 (Box 4)
    - Shari Cohn 1984-1993 (2 folders) (Box 4)
    - Journal Corr. 1993 (Box 4)
    - Journal Corr. 1991-Oct.1993 (Box 4)
    - Referees 1992 (Box 4)
    - SPR Conference 1993& 1994-1995/1996 (Box 4)
    - Vasilescu (Box 4)
    - SPR Research Grants (Box 4)
    - 1989-1990 China (Box 5)
    - Nancy & Carlos 1982-1987 (Box 5)
    - Mary Coyne (Box 5)
    - Cox Supplement 1992 (Box 5)
    - Chinese Symposium 1987 (Box 5)
    - Athlone (Box 5)
    - PA 1991/1992 (Box 5)
    - Conference SPR 1991/1992 (Box 5)
    - Journal 1994 (Box 5)
    - Fryer-Oram Expt. (Box 5)
    - Breederveld 1986-1991 (Box 5)
    - Stevenson & BeloffPaper (Box 5)
    - Dale Stout 1980-1987 (Box 5)
    - Marian Nester 1985/1993 (Box 5)
    - Frank Roberts 1989-1992 (2 folders) (Box 5)
    - Imich Essay &Imich 1987-1991 (Box 5)
    - Cox 1985/1994 (Box 5)
    - Warnambool... (2 folders) (Box 6)
    - D.J. Ellis 1990/1992 (Box 6)
    - Serena Roney-Dougal 1983/1993 (Box 6)
    - F.S. Roberts (2 folders) (Box 6)
    - Thalbourne 1991 (Box 6)
    - Colin Wood (Box 6)
    - WilliamGodwin (Box 6)
- Accession 2002-0245
  - Correspondence (Box 1-5)
    - Correspondence: (Box 1)
      - Beloff Conference (Box 1)
      - Brian MacKenzie, 1989-[present] (Box 1)
      - Massimo Palidoro (Box 1)
      - Richard Wiseman--Hertfordshire (Box 1)
      - Michael Thalbourne, 1993-[present] (Box 1)
      - Alejandro Parda (Box 1)
      - Shari Cohn (Box 1)
      - John Randall (Box 1)
      - Skeptics, 1990-1996--Kendrick Frazier,Paul Kurtz et.al. (Box 1)
      - George Owen--Canada (Box 1)
      - Michael Ward (Box 1)
    - Correspondence: (Box 2)
      - David Lorimer--Beyond theBrain (Box 2)
      - Nicholas Greaves (Box 2)
      - Jon Taylor (Box 2)
      - Reviews (Box 2)
      - Swift, H. (Box 2)
      - Dean Radin (Box 2)
      - U.S.A. (Box 2)
      - Koestler--Jewish LiterarySociety--Michael Scammell (Box 2)
      - Australia and New Zealand, 1990-[present] (Box 2)
    - Correspondence: (Box 3)
      - Japan (Box 3)
      - Adetunji (Box 3)
      - Song, Kong Zhi-Shen, HanChang (Box 3)
      - Africa (Box 3)
      - Braude (Box 3)
      - PersonalCorrespondence (Box 3)
      - Lay Folk--GeneralInterest (Box 3)
      - Randi and Assorted Skeptics, 1990-[present] (Box 3)
      - Tim Haigh, Simon Forsyth--ThePsychic World and Psychic News (Box 3)
      - Frank Dilley (Box 3)
      - Cranks Misc. (Box 3)
      - Adrian Parker--CurrentCorrespondence (Box 3)
      - John Smythies (Box 3)
    - Correspondence: (Box 4)
      - Kerala--India (Box 4)
      - Germany (Box 4)
      - East EuropeanParapsychologists (Box 4)
      - Russian (Box 4)
      - Kappers--Amsterdam (Box 4)
      - Netherlands (Box 4)
      - Breederveld and Dutch Misc. 1992--SRU Belgian (Box 4)
      - Spain--Portugal (Box 4)
      - Hygen--Oslo (Box 4)
      - Alex Imich (Box 4)
    - Correspondence: (Box 5)
      - Paul Edwards (Box 5)
      - South America (Box 5)
      - Paul Smith (Box 5)
      - Rhine Research Center--RichardBroughton (Box 5)
      - Peter Mulacz (Box 5)
      - Carlos Alvarado (Box 5)
      - Titus Rivas (Box 5)
      - Jack Sarfatti (Box 5)
      - Annekatrin Puhle--AdrianParker (Box 5)
      - Smythies/Neuro-philosophy (Box 5)
      - Houran and Lange (Box 5)
      - Emily Cook (Box 5)
      - Misc. Correspondence--arisingfrom publication (Box 5)